<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Tribal Member</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LFhhtssjN-teWCOregn">World of Warcraft 5e</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="tribal-member.xml" url="" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Tribal Member" type="Background" source="GM Binder WOW5E" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_BACKGROUND_TRIBAL_MEMBER">
		<description>
			<p>You were born and raised in the lands of your tribe. Your tribe has a territory on which they reside. You may come from of the many smaller tauren tribes that populate Kalimdor, or from one of the vast expanding tribes of the trolls. Perhaps you are a member of one of the prominent orc clans. You may come from a tribe who have isolated themselves, and have little contact with the outside world, or a tribe that actively trade with civilized societies.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Nature, Survival</li>
				<li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> One type of artisan's tools, one type of musical instrument </li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of common traveler's clothes, a set of artisan's tools (one of your choice), a musical instrument (one of your choice), tribal trinket, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp.</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_AT_ONE_WITH_NATURE" />
			<h4>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h4>
			<p>As a member of a tribe, the community is what matters most, all have to work together and fill their shoes to make the tribe work. Leaving no one behind to pick up the slack.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Nature, Survival, Artisan’s Tool, Musical Insrument</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Tribal Member)" supports="Artisan tools" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Intrument (Tribal Member)" supports="Musical Instrument" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_AT_ONE_WITH_NATURE" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
				<item id="1">I am loyal and will do anything to protect my tribe.</item>
				<item id="2">I speak plainly and often don't understand subtlety.</item>
				<item id="3">I am contemptuous of larger civilizations.</item>
				<item id="4">I do not trust arcane magic and its casters.</item>
				<item id="5">I am naive and friendly to everyone.</item>
				<item id="6">I am baffled by cities and grand architecture.</item>
				<item id="7">I am unshakable and never back down.</item>
				<item id="8">I feel empathy for all that suffer.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Ideal">
				<item id="1">Humility. I am no better or worse than anyone else on this world. (Good)</item>
				<item id="2">Xenophobia. I do not understand the ways of others, but know they are wrong. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="3">Order. Every place has rules which must be followed for everyone's good. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="4">Freedom. There is no rule in the wild, do what you can to live. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="5">Balance. All things and ways of being are natural and necessary. (Neutral)</item>
				<item id="6">Unity. A tribe that works together is strong. (Any)</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Bond">
				<item id="1">My family and my tribe are everything to me.</item>
				<item id="2">I left my tribe to prove my right to a prominent place in the tribe hierarchy.</item>
				<item id="3">I love a prominent tribe member and must prove I am worthy of their love.</item>
				<item id="4">My tribe is threatened and I must protect them.</item>
				<item id="5">My tribe was destroyed and I must have vengeance.</item>
				<item id="6">I was dishonored and thrown out of my tribe, I must prove my worth.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Flaw">
				<item id="1">I don't understand social nuances.</item>
				<item id="2">I drink to excess.</item>
				<item id="3">I don't trust anyone not of my tribe.</item>
				<item id="4">I trust everyone to say what they mean.</item>
				<item id="5">I believe might proves right and will not listen to those who are 'weak'.</item>
				<item id="6">I am insecure since my tribe appears weak compared to larger, more modern societies.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Feature: At One With Nature" type="Background Feature" source="GM Binder WOW5E" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_AT_ONE_WITH_NATURE">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You are intimately familiar with the geography of your home region.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="At One With Nature" />
	</element>

</elements>
