<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Pandaren</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LFhhtssjN-teWCOregn">World of Warcraft 5e</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="pandaren.xml" url="" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Pandaren" type="Race" source="GM Binder WOW5E" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_RACE_PANDAREN">
		<description>
			<p><i>To ask why we fight... is to ask why the leaves fall. It is in their nature. Perhaps, there is a better question. Why do we fight? To protect home, and family... To preserve balance, and bring harmony. For my kind, the true question is, what is worth fighting for?</i></p>
			<p align="right"><i>— Chen Stormstout</i></p>
			<h3>INTRODUCTION</h3>
			<p>The pandaren have long been a mystery to other races of Azeroth, their history stretching back thousands of years, to before the raise of the kaldorei. Denizens of a wondrous and fertile land, the pandaren were slaves to the ancient titan-forged mogu. Through tenacity, diplomacy, and a unique form of unarmed combat, they staged a successful revolution that deposed the mogu, and established the foundation of the pandaren empire that would prosper for thousands of years.</p>
			<p class="indent">As the sundering took place, Pandaria was shrouded in a magical mist that would last for thousand of years. As the years came to an end, the mist around Pandaria unveiled. Drawing the attention of both factions, wishing to claim this 'unexplored' land, and learn of what lied on its surface.</p>
			<h3>HARMONY IN ALL THINGS</h3>
			<p>Pandarens are slow to anger, they prefer a measured solution to problems. It takes a great deal to wound up a pandaren. On their homeland Pandaria, negative emotions are harnessed, and take physical form to wreak havoc on the isle. Pandarens emphasize and cultivate a quiet life of inner harmony and focus. Conflicts, no matter how bitter, are quickly forgotten over cold drinks once the matter is resolved.</p>
			<h3>A SPIRITUAL GUIDE</h3>
			<p>Pandaren have a fierce and deep belief in the connection of the material and spiritual world. In many ways their faith mirrors the ancient beliefs of night elves, and beliefs of the tribal races of Kalimdor.</p>
			<p class="indent">Like the races of Kalimdor, the pandaren follow a shamanistic faith, they worship the Earth Mother and give passage to their dead. They are a society that reacts, rather than being the ones to act first. Many pandarens claim to be the water that flows around a rock -- it never pushes the rocks out of its way, but merely goes around it. This stands as the core of their society, a simple means of everyday life. If they set their mind to a task and fail, then they believe they went about it the wrong way, and try again.</p>
			<h3>COVERED IN FUR</h3>
			<p>Covered in colorful fur from head to toe, pandaren appear like massive humanoid bears towering above the heads of most of Azeroth's inhabitants. They stand far over the head of humans, ranging from just under 7 feet to a few inches short of 8 feet. Pandarens are naturally curvy, only made larger in size by their thick fur, weighing between 310 to 440 pounds. Males stand slightly taller than females, and males are often much heavier than females.</p>
			<p class="indent">Pandaren colorations varies widely, from a dark brown to a golden yellow, one thing that is consistent throughout all pandarens are their white markings, all pandarens have these upon their face, and many also have patches of white on their paws of torso. Pandarens don't have hair, but many stylize their fur on top of their head, letting it grow longer to resemble hair.</p>
			<h3>AFFILIATION</h3>
			<p>Most pandaren are independent, preferring to avoid the con-flict of Alliance and Horde, but few amongst them have decided to join the ranks of either factions, believing that their philosophy aligns with that of the faction.</p>
			<p class="indent">The Tushui pandaren have joined the alliance, believing that one should live a life through meditation, rigorous training, and moral convictions. The Huojin pandaren have joined the horde. believing that inaction is the greatest injustice, and that there is no shame in defending one's home and loved ones, regardless of the cost.</p>
			<p class="indent">Pandaria have been hidden from the world for many thousand years, the inhabitants of Azeroth are new to the pandarens. Because of this they have no hatred or distrust for any of the new races they've met.</p>
			<h3>NAMES</h3>
			<p>Pandaren naming practices are similar to those of humans, each pandaren are given a name at birth, and carries on the family name of their parents. Some pandaren are known to take a new family name reflecting their own achievements in life, yet such practices are uncommon.</p>
			<p><strong>Male Names:</strong> Fan Su, Tan Delan, Tian Fu, Fan-Su, Zi Ling, Gao, Bai, Wei He, Xun Ming, Dong-Gun</p>
			<p><strong>Female Names:</strong> Sujin, Zemin, Seul-Gi, Heng Lei, Sun-Mi, Zheng, Yan, Wei Zhelan, Xuefeng, Li, Liuxian</p>
			<p><strong>Family Names:</strong> Caskriver, Drumfriends, Wisespear, Keenwalker, Calmbrow, Mellowcoil, Ironshadow, Wildfur</p>
			<h3>PANDAREN TRAITS</h3>
			<p>Your pandaren character has certain traits deriving from their ancient heritage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Ability Score Increase.</i></strong> Your Wisdom score increases by 1, and your Charisma score increases by 2.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Age.</i></strong> Pandaren age much like humans, reaching adult-hood in their late teens, and generally die before they reach their first century.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Alignment.</i></strong> Pandaren are a peaceful race, and for most parts tend to their own, making many pandarens neutral or good aligned. Finding an evil aligned pandaren is unusual.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Size.</i></strong> Most pandaren stands just short of 7 feet tall and average about 260 pounds, you will never find a pandaren who is 'slim'. Your size is medium.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Speed.</i></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Gourmand.</i></strong> You gain proficiency with the artisan's tool (cook's utensils) and (brewer's supplies).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Iron Palms.</i></strong> Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 + Strength modifier bludgeoning damage on a hit.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Pandaren Resilience.</i></strong> You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Pandaren Weapon Training.</i></strong> You have proficiency with the club, quarterstaff, and spear.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Quaking Palms.</i></strong> When you hit another creature with an unarmed strike, you may use your innate powers to attempt to disable the target. The target must succeed on a Consti-tution saving throw, or be stunned until the end of your next turn. Wisdom is your saving throw ability for this feature. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><i>Languages.</i></strong> You can speak, read, and write, Common and Mogu. Mogu is the language of Pandaria, forced upon the inhabitants of Pandaria by the mogu empire. It is a strange and unfamiliar language to the rest of Azeroth, with a multitude of words meaning one common thing.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Fan Su, Tan Delan, Tian Fu, Fan-Su, Zi Ling, Gao, Bai, Wei He, Xun Ming, Dong-Gun</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Sujin, Zemin, Seul-Gi, Heng Lei, Sun-Mi, Zheng, Yan, Wei Zhelan, Xuefeng, Li, Liuxian</set>
			<set name="names" type="surname">Caskriver, Drumfriends, Wisespear, Keenwalker, Calmbrow, Mellowcoil, Ironshadow, Wildfur</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} {{surname}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="2" />
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_LANGUAGE_COMMON"/>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_LANGUAGE_MOGU"/>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_LANGUAGE_PANDAREN"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_COOKS_UTENSILS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_BREWERS_SUPPLIES" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CLUB" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_QUARTERSTAFF" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SPEAR" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_RACIAL_TRAIT_PANDAREN_IRON_PALMS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_RACIAL_TRAIT_PANDAREN_PANDAREN_RESILIENCE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_RACIAL_TRAIT_PANDAREN_QUAKING_PALM" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Iron Palms" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder WOW5E" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_RACIAL_TRAIT_PANDAREN_IRON_PALMS">
		<description>
			<p>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 + Strength modifier bludgeoning damage on a hit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 + {{pandaren iron palms:count}} bludgeoning damage on a hit.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
      <stat name="pandaren iron palms:count" value="strength:modifier" />
    </rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Pandaren Resilience" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder WOW5E" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_RACIAL_TRAIT_PANDAREN_PANDAREN_RESILIENCE">
		<description>
			<p>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
    </rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Quaking Palm" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder WOW5E" id="ID_GMBINDER_WOW5E_RACIAL_TRAIT_PANDAREN_QUAKING_PALM">
		<description>
			<p> When you hit another creature with an unarmed strike, you may use your innate powers to attempt to disable the target. The target must succeed on a Consti-tution saving throw, or be stunned until the end of your next turn. Wisdom is your saving throw ability for this feature. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description> When you hit another creature with an unarmed strike, you may use your innate powers to attempt to disable the target. The target must succeed on a Consti-tution saving throw, or be stunned until the end of your next turn. Wisdom is your saving throw ability for this feature.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules />
	</element>

</elements>
